Welcome home, Father!
I'm home, Selim.
Here.
You can go ahead and open it.
Okay!
Thank you very much!
Happy tenth birthday, Selim.
Where are we?
We're at you-know-who's place.
"You-know-who"?
The one who is making you homunculi search for the Philosopher's Stone?
That's not all.
The one who found us,
brought us together, and nurtured us.
You're being tricked—all you homunculi who want to become human.
Those who are being tricked are fools.
What about you?
Yeah, I know.
That person just wants the
Philosopher's Stone to use personally.
So what?
As long as I get to see humans suffer,
that's good enough for me.
Hey, now, your body is precious.
Don't do anything reckless.
Shoot!
How many people do you think Scar killed to make you the Philosopher's Stone?
Of the soldiers who
charged into Liore,
seven thousand of them
disappeared in an instant.
They're not dead.
They're all right here.
Oh yeah, and the guys that died long ago in Ishbal who were in Scar's right arm
are locked away
inside there as well.
Awesome, awesome!
You've got thousands—tens of thousands—of lives there inside you.
We should put them
to good use, huh?!
I should have died.
Back then...
and back then...
and back then too.
So then, why am I still alive?
Brother?
Dad?
The Philosopher's Stone.
Those who obtain it are set free from the Law of Equivalent Exchange.
There is no need to pay a price
in order to obtain something, either.
We sought it and found it.
Edward-san!
What were you doing?
Sorry. Is this the place?
Yes. This is definitely the place.
Show me one more time.
Dad once came here to Central,
looking for a way to refine the red water.
He wound up going to a place called the 5th Laboratory,
and there, he met up
with a certain alchemist.
That person told him that there was some indispensable element
that was necessary to transmute the red water
all the way into a Philosopher's Stone
and hinted to him
that it was human lives.
He also showed him
where the real laboratory was.
The 5th Laboratory was nothing more than a secret entrance.
In fact, there was an even larger human experimentation lab.
This does indeed appear to be the place that we have been searching for.
I'm going alone.
But Al-kun is in danger,
though we don't know what kind, right?
It's all right. He's just
gotten a little lost. That's all.
Ed...
The reason why we showed you what was in this journal...
was not because we wanted you to make a Philosopher's Stone.
I know. I'm not going there
to create a Philosopher's Stone.
Believe me.
Come back to us now!
Come back to us alive!
According to Dad's journal,
you descend from the temple of the ancient religion
and go farther and farther underground,
and then suddenly...
there's another city,
all tucked away beneath Central.
Dad said that judging by its style of architecture,
it looked like the city was nearly four hundred years old.
There's a legend that says
that the city that was there,
where Central is now,
vanished overnight.
Dad says he thought that there might have been alchemists who were performing
some kind of experiment and may have closed up the whole city underground.
The people of the city
were all sacrificed
to be used in their
Philosopher's Stone.
And then, to hide the fact that there weren't any people left,
they made the city itself disappear.
There's actually someone who thought that up?
Is anyone there?!
I know you're here! You knew about everything, didn't you,
Pop?!
No, Gluttony.
Be patient.
This girl's body is
very important, after all.
So pretty. It's no wonder why Ed and Al would like you.
They are his children.
Hey, what happened to Lust?!
Yes, what could have
happened to her?
That's right, I need to
get my dress ready.
We have to be pretty
when we greet him.
Somebody's here.
My, that was quick.
Where is he?
Wrath...
Where is he?!
What a pest!
Where's the Philosopher's Stone?!
What's the meaning of this?
Where is he?! Where did he go?!
I thought he was keeping an eye on Edward.
Tell me, Envy! Please!
That's what I thought I told him to do.
Please! Give me the
Philosopher's Stone, quick!
Wrath, you have to be a good boy,
or I won't make you human.
There's no time for that!
Mama... Mama is going to be all gone!
Mama?
He means Sloth.
Sloth is not your mama.
Homunculi do not have mothers.
Bring Mama back to life! Please!
Don't talk like you're human.
Mama... Mama!
Mama!
Envy!
Please!
What do you think
you can do in your shape?
What power!
It's only natural that
Edward Elric would use Automail.
This is fun!
Someone like you is a soldier?
That explains why no one has realized who the Führer is!
It's still not too late for you. Become one of my soldiers.
We are ready to wage war on
the north, the west, and the south.
The time has come for
the continent to be united.
Not interested.
In that case, die!
Your pupils will be
following you soon as well.
What are you doing?!
I am your superior officer!
You too?!
Izumi-san!
Where's... Ed?
By now, both brothers should be at the place that was written about in that journal.
You all believed... in those boys?
Believing in and protecting children
is the job of an adult.
That's what someone once told me.
Rose?
Ed...
You finally came.
Now, that should
teach you a lesson.
Don't start any fights
with these guys.
You really don't ever learn
unless you get hurt.
Something the matter?
I think I just figured something out.
Figured what out?
Hughes-san said something
before he died.
"What if everything was backwards?"
I never understood what he meant.
And you figured it out?
We've been thinking that the homunculi
were trying to create a Philosopher's Stone.
But what if it was
the other way around?
They wait until it is just barely completed, and then take it away.
Then they eliminate everyone
who can prove it ever happened.
What's left is a rumor that says if you come near the Philosopher's Stone, you'll be destroyed.
In time, people become afraid of the Philosopher's Stone...
So they'll keep away from it?
But that would almost make them good people, wouldn't it?
They're making sure people stay out of danger, after all.
What's more,
no matter how dangerous it is,
I'll bet that people will
still go on looking for it.
I wonder how Edward-san and his brother are doing.
I'm sure they're getting along fine.
That much is certain.
Pain that teaches a lesson, huh?
But God is the only one who can teach that kind of lesson.
R-Rose, what are you doing here?
I've been waiting for you
a long, long time.
Ed, I...
Rose...
Rose, was Al brought here?
What exactly is this place?
My baby...
You should have danced with her.
She's been waiting for you ever since we fled here.
You're despicable.
Lyra, you brought Rose here?
There's an old city that
only alchemists know of.
That's what Dante-sensei told me.
Speaking of Dante-san, I still
haven't heard how she was killed.
She was killed by
that homunculus Greed.
I thought I told you.
That is a lie.
A lie?
The transmutation circle that was left in Dante-san's house
was one that could keep
a homunculus from moving.
There were bones from the man
on whom Greed was based.
Greed shouldn't have been able to
take action against Dante-san.
Are you sure?
Still, Dante-san definitely is dead.
But supposing that what was there
was nothing more than a shell
that her soul had sloughed off...
What are you saying?
Let's suppose there were people who used the power of the Philosopher's Stone
to move from one body to another
and who have lived for hundreds of years.
Back there, you made it
look like you were dead
and then took over Lyra's body.
Isn't that right?!
Ed, stop! I am—
That was close.
When did you see the gate, Lyra?
You transmuted without
using a transmutation circle.
That's my answer, Dante!
When did you figure it out,
Edward Elric?
Then it's true?
I've really come to like this body.
So then, what number is she?
Who knows?
It hasn't been ten yet, though.
After all, I have to use the
Philosopher's Stone each time.
Did you wipe out the residents of this city to make your Philosopher's Stone?
Yes, the same as with the nation to the east,
which was destroyed overnight.
I should mention, though,
that I was not the one who made them.
Hohenheim of Light...
You shouldn't address
your own father like that.
So he's prolonged his life
the same way? For what reason?
Because we deserve to.
You covertly create
the Philosopher's Stone
just so you can use it to extend your own lives.
You think you can
get away with that?!
Humans cannot use
the Philosopher's Stone.
Is that why, when people fail to
complete a Philosopher's Stone,
you obliterate everything
and leave behind the story
that destruction befalls those who get too close to the Philosopher's Stone?
Yes, to keep people from getting
too close to the Philosopher's Stone.
And for those who
still get too close,
we take it from them at the last minute
and use it carefully.
After all, there's no telling what humans would do
if they were given a
Philosopher's Stone, right?
I do it to keep foolish people from destroying the world.
You could say that I have extended my life to protect the world.
To keep humans from doing anything foolish with the Philosopher's Stone.
Cut the crap! You're human too!
Not anymore.
Lust!
Lust! Where's Lust?!
What a shame.
I was looking forward to entering this girl's body
and making love to
Hohenheim's son.
Rose's body is next, is it?!
Yes. I have obtained a
Philosopher's Stone again, and all.
Al?! Where's Al?!
Where's Lust?!
What happened to Lust?!
Try asking him, Gluttony.
Lust!
Lust! Where's Lust?!
She's dead.
And it was my fault.
Lust... is dead?
Yeah. Your pal Wrath sealed her up.
Gluttony?
Lust...
Gluttony!
Here I come!
I knew it.
Repeatedly bonding just your soul is not something you can continue doing forever.
Equivalent exchange!
That's the backlash from performing that idiocy over and over!
Equivalent exchange?
Do you still believe in
that childish theory?
It's no theory!
It's the law of alchemy—
no, of the whole world!
You're the one who
said so, aren't you?
That in order to obtain anything,
it requires something of equal value?
That's something that
only a child would say.
Like "make everything equal," or "that wouldn't be fair."
However, there's no such thing as equivalent exchange.
That's absurd!
There is a cost required in order for you to obtain something...
In that case, if you reverse it—
if you pay a price, you are certain to obtain something, right?
That's right. That's why people
put forth an effort to pay the price.
But there's something
strange about that.
After all, even if you
pay the same price,
you can't always necessarily obtain the same thing.
Well, that's...
There's the State Alchemist Exam, right?
In order to pass it, many people
spend time studying. That's a cost.
But only a handful of people
actually pass it.
Everyone may start out the same
when they learn alchemy,
but huge differences arise in their actual abilities.
And people's lives
are not all equal, either.
If nobody does anything,
that baby is going to die, right?
Stop!
It really would be easy
for me to kill it.
If I do, was the baby
born only in order to die?
The baby is paying the price of desperately trying to survive.
Yet is death the only thing
they're going to get for that?
Elsewhere, there are people who kill others
and continue to go on living.
No matter how hard you may try to live, when it's time for you to die, you die.
When you compare that to
people who don't make any effort
yet are afforded riches and power
and live lives of happiness,
it's quite unfair, isn't it?
The world is quite cruel.
Which is why you might say
it's so beautiful.
Cut the sophistry!
My baby...
Equivalent exchange is an excuse that the weak use to comfort themselves.
They tell themselves that by paying a price, it's supposed to make themselves happier.
This baby doesn't
have to make any excuses!
You're his son, all right.
Ouch...
What is this?
What's going on here?
My eyes...
Who is this?
What's that?
Edward-kun!
What are you doing?!
It's an air raid!
Hurry up!
Wait! Pop, what are you doing here?!
What is this place?!
"Pop"? Edward-kun,
what are you talking about?
I thought you were at
Dante-san's place!
What is this place?!
What's happened to me?!
My face... my hand?
Are you my son Edward?
Of course I am!
What are you doing here?
I don't know...
Let's go! They're coming!
Who do you mean, "they"?!
Zeppelins!
Zeppelins?
Fullmetal Alchemist...
Episode 50: "Death"